Inventory of the John Elbert Elliott papers 1901-1980
Hoover Institution Archives
John Elbert Elliott papers
1901-1980
Elliott, John Elbert, 1887-1980.
81095
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
53 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (26.4 linear feet)
Includes letters, photographs, clippings, printed matter, and memorabilia of an American oil geologist, engineer, and entrepreneur.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Arthur A. Cervi miscellany, Hoover Institution Archives
Charles H. White papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1887 Born, Bozeman, Montana
1897 Moved to the Monterey and Salinas area of California
1906 Graduated from Monterey High School
1907 Member, Western Pacific Railway survey party in the Feather River Canyon
1911-1912 Chief statistician, Associated Oil Company, Taft, California
1912 A.B. in geology & mining, Stanford University
1912-1913 Assistant chief geologist, Caribbean Petroleum Company (subsidiary of the Barber Asphalt Company), Venezuela
1913 First American geologist to become a regular employee of the Royal Dutch Petroleum Group in the United States
1913-1915 Geologist, Shell Oil Company of California, San Francisco
1915-1920 Chief Geologist, Shell Oil Company of California, San Francisco
1918- Member, American Institute of Mining, Metallurgical and Petroleum Engineers (AIME)
1919- Member, American Association of Petroleum Geologists (AAPG)
1921 Associate professor of petroleum technology, Stanford University
1921 Moved to Los Angeles, California
1921-1939 President and general manager, Elliott Core Drilling Company
1922-1939 With Floyd C. Merritt, formed the firm Elliott and Merritt, working as a consulting engineer and geologist, Los Angeles With Merritt, organized and operated the Elliott Oil Companies (also known as the Elliott Petroleum Co.), located in Santa Fe Springs
1923 Author, "Core Drilling with Rotary Tools in California," Bulletin of the American Association of Petroleum Geologists
1928-1929 Vice president, American Association of Petroleum Geologists (AAPG)
1929 Pioneered the use of geological map-making through airplane travel
1940-1942 Independent petroleum engineer and operator
1942-1944 Major, Chemical Warfare Service, United States Army
1944 Moved to Austin, Texas
1944-1960 Independent petroleum geologist
1960- Estate manager, semi-retired
1962 Recipient, Anthony F. Lucas Gold Metal of the American Institute of Mining, Metallurgical and Petroleum Engineers
1966- Member, American Institute of Professional Geologists (AIPG)
1968 Selected as the Republican presidential elector for the 10th district in Texas
1970 Elected honorary member of the American Association of Petroleum Geologists
1972 Named honorary chairman of the Texas delegation to the Electoral College
1980 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection was originally housed in a series of binders that served as personal and professional scrapbooks of John E. "Brick" Elliott, a petroleum industry businessman, geologist, and consultant who created and popularized the core barrel technique for drilling and invented the double-barreled rotary core. The eclectic mix of materials, including letters, photographs, clippings, and ephemera, provides a snapshot of the United States in the 20th century, particularly focusing on the oil industry, the Republican Party, and political and civil rights issues in the 1960s and 1970s.
The Scrapbooks, which make up the majority of the collection, follow the timeline of Elliott's life, documenting his career, travels, and interests. They merge professional and personal material, containing photographs, correspondence, and printed matter from Elliott's life and work, which took him around the United States and abroad. Many scrapbooks document Elliott's travels or contain materials documenting Elliott's work in the oil industry, including his role in the Elliott Core Drilling Company. The scrapbooks also include materials on people Elliott knew at various times in his life, such as Stanford classmates and oil industry businessmen.
Elliott was a Stanford University alumnus. The collection contains photographs and memorabilia from his years at Stanford (1907-1912), as well as documentation of his activities as an alumnus, materials on football at Stanford, and clippings on student protests in the 1960s.
An active member of the Republican Party, Elliott served as the Republican presidential elector for the 10th district in Texas. The collection contains correspondence and material from his political involvement, as well as printed material covering a wide variety of political and economic issues. Additionally, Elliott attended yearly meetings and reunions of various groups, including the Bohemian Club and the American Association of Petroleum Geologists, which are documented in his scrapbooks.
The Correspondence, subject file, and printed matter contain material not included in Elliott's scrapbooks, including printed matter on Stanford and the oil industry.
The Motion picture film contains a color film of highlights from a Rose Bowl game, while the Oversize material includes drawings of Stanford.
Engineers.; Petroleum industry and trade.
- Scrapbooks, 1901-1980 (Box 1-50)
  Scope and Contents Note
  Includes photographs, postcards, correspondence, printed matter, maps, and ephemera. The scrapbooks are arranged by a combination of original binder numbers and dates of material. Although the majority of the scrapbooks document a fixed period of years in Elliott's life, he often included material from earlier or later dates. For example, the scrapbook of Elliott's trip to Europe in 1933 includes printed matter on Europe from the 1960s and 1970s. Dates given for the scrapbooks are based on the dates of all material in that scrapbook. Additionally, some binder numbers for years in the 1970s do not follow the overall numbering scheme, denoting the first binder in that year as number 1, while other binders (especially those documenting Stanford) were not given a number or were given a number with dates that do not match the chronological sequence exhibited in the rest of the scrapbooks. These scrapbooks are arranged chronologically within the series.
  - "Leland Stanford Junior University, Breakers,", 1901-1964 (Folder 1: 1-5)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes material on the Coyote Club
  - Stanford University, Breakers Club, and oil industry (Binder 4), 1909-1974 (Folder 1: 6-8)
  - Stanford University, Breakers Club, and first jobs in oil industry (Binder 4) (contd.), 1909-1974 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Alaska trip for Shell Oil Company, professorship at Stanford, and Elliott Core Drilling Company (Binder 8), 1916-1975 (Folder 2: 2-6)
    Includes paper by Elliott and clippings on World War I
  - Oil industry, camping photographs, and clubs (Binder 9), 1922-1966 (Folder 2: 7-8)
  - Oil industry, camping photographs, and clubs (Binder 9) (contd.), 1922-1966 (Folder 3: 1-2)
  - Elliott Core Drilling Company and American Association of Petroleum Geologists (Binder 10), circa 1927-1974 (Folder 3: 3-5)
    Includes pilot logbook and clipping on Elliott traveling by plane
  - "Company Planes, President Hoover, Ruth's Fish" (Binder 11), 1929-1974 (Folder 3: 6-7)
  - Correspondence, Elliott Core Drilling Company, drilling jumbos, and ranching photographs (Binder 12), 1930-1972 (Folder 4: 1-4)
    Includes photographs of Elliott detachable jackhammer bits and parts
  - "Xth Olympiad in Los Angeles" (Binder 13), 1932 (Folder 4: 5-7)
  - Arizona, Long Beach, Hawaii, and Wildcat annual meeting on yacht (Binder 14), 1933-1970 (Folder 5: 1-4)
  - "Europe" (Binder 15), 1933-1968 (Folder 5: 5-8)
  - "Europe" (Binder 16), 1934-1967 (Folder 6: 1-4)
  - "Europe" (Binder 16A), 1934-1973 (Folder 6: 5-7)
  - "Spain and Argentina" (Binder 17), 1934-1966 (Folder 6: 8)
  - "Spain and Argentina" (Binder 17) (contd.), 1934-1966 (Folder 7: 1-3)
  - "Argentina, Venezuela, Trinidad, and Brazil" (Binder 18), 1934-1965 (Folder 7: 4-7)
  - "Colombia, Panama, and Costa Rica" (Binder 19), 1934-1968 (Folder 7: 8-9)
    Includes Elliott Core Drilling Company material
  - "Colombia, Panama, and Costa Rica" (Binder 19) (contd.), 1934-1968 (Folder 8: 1-2)
  - "The Americas" (Binder 20), 1937-1970 (Folder 8: 3-6)
  - "South America" (Binder 21), 1938-1973 (Folder 8: 7-9)
  - "South America" (Binder 21) (contd.), 1938-1973 (Folder 9: 1)
  - "South America" (Binder 22), Includes Elliott Core Drilling Company material, 1939-1966 (Folder 9: 2-5)
  - "South America," Equator and Peru (Binder 23), 1939-1972 (Folder 9: 6-9)
  - Binder of 1939, "South America,", 1964-1969 (Folder 10: 1-4)
  - "South America, Martin Fierro" (Binder 25), 1939-1972 (Folder 10: 5-8)
  - United States (Binder 26), 1940-1974 (Folder 11: 1-4)
    Includes report on Salt Lake Oil Field by Elliott
  - Texas and Mexico (Binder 29), 1944-1969 (Folder 11: 5-8)
    Includes Ruth Elliott/Red Cross photographs and clippings
  - California, Egypt, Mexico, Americas, Bohemian Club, and American Association of Petroleum Geologists (Binder 30), 1948-1970 (Folder 12: 1-4)
  - South America and Americas (Binder 31), 1951-1968 (Folder 12: 5-8)
    Includes printed matter on General MacArthur
  - Texas politics and Bohemian Club (Binder 32), 1952-1953 (Folder 13: 1-3)
    Includes travelogue and "South of the Border" by Francis (Frank) E. Rehm
  - "Presidents of the U.S.,", 1953-1972 (Folder 13: 4-7)
  - "Palico" (Binder 33), 1954-1973 (Folder 13: 8-9)
    Includes American Association of Petroleum Geologists photographs, Mexico materials, and letter from Herbert Hoover, Jr.
  - "Palico" (Binder 33) (contd.), 1954-1973 (Folder 14: 1-2)
  - Association of Petroleum Geologists, Bohemian Club, and South America (Binder 34), 1958-1975 (Folder 14: 3-6)
  - Association of Petroleum Geologists, Bohemian Club, and inauguration of Earl Rudder (Binder 35), 1959-1966 (Folder 14: 7-10)
  - "Stanford Class of 1911 50th and 1961 Ballot" (Binder 56), 1961-1969 (Folder 15: 1-4)
  - "Montana and the West" (Binder 1), 1961-1970 (Folder 15: 5-8)
  - Binder of 1962, Anthony F. Lucas Gold Medal, 1959-1962 (Folder 15: 9-10)
    Includes interview of Elliott
  - Binder of 1962, Anthony F. Lucas Gold Medal (contd.), 1959-1962 (Folder 16: 1-2)
  - Binder of 1963, Oil industry, United States trips, and American Association of Petroleum Geologists, 1963-1964 (Folder 16: 3-6)
  - "Special Articles,", 1963-1977 (Folder 16: 7-9)
    Includes magazine clippings on nature, the oil industry, and history
  - "Special Articles" (contd.), 1963-1977 (Folder 17: 1)
  - "Breakers Club" and California (Binder 39), 1963-1967 (Folder 17: 2-5)
  - John F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson, and United States trips (Binder 40), 1963-1964 (Folder 17: 6-8)
  - John F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson, and United States trips (Binder 40) (contd.), 1963-1964 (Folder 18: 1)
  - Trip of 1964, "Alaska and Canada" (Binder 41), 1959-1969 (Folder 18: 2-6)
  - Binder of 1964, "Canada and Barry Goldwater" (Binder 42), 1947-1972 (Folder 18: 7-10)
  - Binder of 1964, "Canada and Barry Goldwater" (Binder 42) (contd.), 1947-1972 (Folder 19: 1)
  - "Southwest and East" United States (Binder 43), 1964-1972 (Folder 19: 2-5)
  - Bohemian Club, politics, and United States trips (Binder 44), 1964 (Folder 19: 6-9)
  - Political clippings and oil industry (Binder 45), 1964-1966 (Folder 20: 1-4)
    Includes biographical article on Elliott
  - "Stanford,", 1964-1966 (Folder 20: 5-9)
    Includes one photograph from 1910
  - Republican Party and death of Winston Churchill (Binder 46), 1965 (Folder 21: 1-3)
  - Correspondence, politics, and Texas (Binder 47), 1965 (Folder 21: 4-7)
  - "Mexico" (Binder 48), 1965-1969 (Folder 22: 1-3)
  - Texas, New Mexico, and Arizona (Binder 49), 1955-1968 (Folder 22: 4-7)
  - Bohemian Club, Las Vegas, and Petroleum Production Pioneers (Binder 50), 1963-1965 (Folder 23: 1-3)
  - John F. Kennedy, United States trips, oil and geology groups (Binder 51), 1965-1966 (Folder 23: 4-6)
  - "Big Game," Stanford football (Binder 52), 1965-1966 (Folder 23: 7-9)
  - Politics, Texas, and clippings (Binder 53), 1966 (Folder 24: 1-4)
  - Oil industry and International Petroleum Exposition (Binder 54), 1965-1969 (Folder 24: 5-7)
  - Father's Day, politics, and Republican Party (Binder 55), 1966-1967 (Folder 24: 8-9)
  - Father's Day, politics, and Republican Party (Binder 55) (contd.), 1966-1967 (Folder 25: 1-2)
  - Oil industry, Republican Party, and Texas (Binder 56), 1965-1966 (Folder 25: 3-6)
  - Russia, Atlanta, politics, and geology (Binder 6), 1966-1967 (Folder 25: 7-9)
    Originally titled "Faulting Off Africa"
  - Republican Party, Stanford University, and American Institute of Mining, Metallurgical and Petroleum Engineers (Binder 57), 1967 (Folder 26: 1-3)
  - Republican Party, American Association of Petroleum Geologists, and personal photographs (Binder 58), 1966-1967 (Folder 26: 4-6)
  - Arizona Highways magazine, political clippings, and personal photographs (Binder 59), 1967 (Folder 26: 7-9)
  - Bohemian Club, Republican Party, personal photographs, and oil industry publications (Binder 60), 1967 (Folder 27: 1-4)
  - "Baja California," United States, and personal photographs (Binder 7), 1967 (Folder 27: 5-8)
  - "Stanford University,", 1967-1968 (Folder 28: 1-5)
  - Binder of 1968, Bohemian Club, Republican Party and State Convention, and personal photographs, 1967-1972 (Folder 28: 6-9)
  - Republican Party, and American Institute of Mining, Metallurgical and Petroleum Engineers (Binder 64), 1968 (Folder 29: 1-4)
  - HemisFair (world's fair), Republican Party and Texas Republican State Convention, articles on race relations, and personal photographs (Binder 66), 1968 (Folder 29: 5-8)
  - Republican Party and Richard Nixon (Binder 68), 1968-1969 (Folder 30: 1-3)
  - Republican Party, Richard Nixon, and Lincoln Motorcar book (Binder 69), 1968-1969 (Folder 30: 4-6)
  - Political clippings, American Association of Petroleum Geologists, and personal photographs, 1968-1969 (Folder 30: 7-9)
    Includes one article from 1966
  - "Stanford University,", 1968-1969 (Folder 31: 1-4)
    Includes photograph of April 3rd Movement and clippings on protests
  - Republican Party, correspondence from Joseph Jensen, and Washington D.C. photographs (Binder 71), 1969 (Folder 31: 5-7)
  - Republican Party, personal photographs, and clippings (Binder 72), 1969 (Folder 31: 8)
  - Republican Party, personal photographs, and clippings (Binder 72) (contd.), 1969 (Folder 32: 1-2)
  - Bohemian Club, Republican Party, economics, and clippings on Edward Ted Kennedy (Binder 73), 1969-1973 (Folder 32: 3-5)
  - Oil industry, Republican Party, politics, and economics (Binder 74), 1968-1969 (Folder 32: 6-8)
  - Politics, Richard Nixon, Spiro Agnew, Republican Party, and American Institute of Professional Geologists (Binder 75), 1969 (Folder 33: 1-4)
  - American Association of Petroleum Geologists, Republican Party, and Richard Nixon (Binder 76), 1967-1969 (Folder 33: 5-8)
  - "Stanford,", 1969 (Folder 33: 9)
    Includes materials on student protests
  - "Stanford" (contd.), 1969 (Folder 34: 1-3)
  - Political and economic clippings, Republican Party, Stanford, and Joe Jensen materials (Binder 78), 1970 (Folder 34: 4-7)
    Includes correspondence on dinner honoring Elliott
  - Richard Nixon, personal photographs, clippings on civil rights and economics, and Marine Military Academy (Binder 79), 1967-1972 (Folder 34: 8-9)
  - Richard Nixon, personal photographs, clippings on civil rights and economics, and Marine Military Academy (Binder 79)(contd.), 1967-1972 (Folder 35: 1-2)
  - Republican Party, dinner honoring Spiro Agnew, Marine Military Academy, and clippings on women's movement and social issues (Binder 80), 1970 (Folder 35: 3-5)
  - American Association of Petroleum Geologists and Republican Party (Binder 81), 1970 (Folder 35: 6-8)
  - Bohemian Club, synchronized swimming, and Republican Party (Binder 82), 1970 (Folder 36: 1-3)
    Includes photograph of George Bush
  - Republican Party, Richard Nixon, and dinner honoring Spiro Agnew (Binder 6), 1970 (Folder 36: 4-6)
  - "Stanford Football,", 1970-1974 (Folder 36: 7)
  - "Stanford Football" (contd.), 1970-1974 (Folder 37: 1-2)
  - Oil industry, politics, economics, and social issues (Binder 1), 1971 (Folder 37: 3-5)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson Library, Museum of the Rockies, and Republican Party (Binder 2), 1971 (Folder 37: 6-9)
  - Bohemian Club, and clippings on economics and politics (Binder 3), 1971 (Folder 38: 1-3)
  - "Special Articles,", 1972-1977 (Folder 38: 4-7)
    Includes historical articles, nature articles, and clippings from The Smithsonian
  - "National Issues," clippings on Richard Nixon, and nomination of Elliott for Republican presidential elector in Texas (Binder 1), 1972 (Folder 38: 8-9)
  - "National Issues," clippings on Richard Nixon, and nomination of Elliott for Republican presidential elector in Texas (Binder 1) (contd.), 1972 (Folder 39: 1)
  - "National Issues," clippings on Richard Nixon, and Bohemian Club (Binder 2), 1972 (Folder 39: 2-5)
    Includes letter from George Bush
  - "National Issues," Republican Party State Convention in Texas, article on Elliott, and Brazil postcards (Binder 3), 1972 (Folder 39: 6-9)
  - "Stanford University,", 1972-1977 (Folder 40: 1-3)
    Includes manual prepared for the Committee on Special Gifts, Trusts, and Bequests and information on giving to Stanford
  - Richard Nixon and Vietnam War (Binder [1]), 1973 (Folder 40: 4-7)
  - Republican Party, Richard Nixon, and Watergate (Binder 2), 1973 (Folder 40: 8-9)
  - Republican Party, Richard Nixon, and Watergate (Binder 2) (contd.), 1973 (Folder 41: 1)
  - Richard Nixon, Watergate, and Spiro Agnew (Binder 3), 1973 (Folder 41: 2-3)
    Includes letters from Spiro Agnew and George Bush
  - Richard Nixon, Watergate, energy crisis/oil shortage, and space exploration (Binder 4), 1973-1974 (Folder 41: 4-7)
  - "Stanford University,", 1973-1978 (Folder 42: 1-3)
  - Energy crisis/oil shortage, Middle East, economics, predictions, Richard Nixon (Binder 1), 1974 (Folder 42: 4-7)
  - Economics, oil industry, Richard Nixon, Watergate (Binder 2), 1974 (Folder 42: 8-11)
    Includes telegram from Elliott to Nixon
  - George M. Mardikian correspondence and clippings, Richard Nixon, economics, and Bohemian Club (Binder 3), 1974 (Folder 43: 1-4)
  - "National Issues," Richard Nixon, Gerald Ford, Hoover Institution centennial, and economics (Binder 4), 1974 (Folder 43: 5-7)
    Includes note signed by Gerald Ford and photographs of Elliott's office
  - Economics, politics, and Gerald Ford (Binder 5), 1974 (Folder 43: 8-9)
  - Economics, politics, and Gerald Ford (Binder 5) (contd.), 1974 (Folder 44: 1)
  - Gerald Ford, oil industry, photographs of Ruth Elliott with azaleas, and clippings on politics and economics (Binder 1), 1975 (Folder 44: 2-5)
  - Vietnam, U.S. News & World Report, and clippings on politics and economics (Binder 2), 1975 (Folder 44: 6-9)
  - Personal photographs, oil industry, and clippings on economics and politics (Binder 3), 1975 (Folder 45: 1-3)
  - Gerald Ford, personal photographs, Christmas cards, and political clippings (Binder 4), 1975 (Folder 45: 4-7)
  - Jimmy Carter, clippings on various countries and politics (Binder 1), 1976-1977 (Folder 45: 8-9)
  - Jimmy Carter, clippings on various countries and politics (Binder 1) (contd.), 1976-1977 (Folder 46: 1-2)
  - "National Issues," Gerald Ford, George M. Mardikian correspondence and clippings, and personal photographs (Binder 1), 1976 (Folder 46: 3-6)
    Includes letter from Gerald Ford
  - "National Issues," women's movement, and presidential election (Binder 2), 1976 (Folder 46: 7-10)
  - Jimmy Carter, Gerald Ford, and clippings on various countries (Binder 1), 1977 (Folder 47: 1-4)
  - Jimmy Carter, energy, and clippings on politics and economics (Binder 2), 1977 (Folder 47: 5-8)
  - "National Issues," Bohemian Club, and clippings on politics and economics (Binder 3), 1977 (Folder 47: 9-10)
  - "National Issues," Bohemian Club, and clippings on politics and economics (Binder 3) (contd.), 1977 (Folder 48: 1-2)
  - "National Issues," clippings on Bert Lance, Jimmy Carter, South Africa, Russia, the Middle East, Panama Canal, and various countries (Binder 4), 1977 (Folder 48: 3-6)
  - Clippings on Jimmy Carter, Bert Lance, Panama Canal, various countries, and economics (Binder 1), 1978 (Folder 48: 7-10)
  - May Bradford Shockley memorial, Jimmy Carter, clippings on oil industry, various countries, and Richard Nixon (Binder 2), 1977-1978 (Folder 49: 1-4)
  - Clippings on Allan Bakke, Jimmy Carter, various countries, economics, and politics (Binder 3), 1978 (Folder 49: 5-8)
  - Letters about Austin Inaugural Committee, Bohemian Club, and oil industry, clippings on Jimmy Carter, economics, and politics (Binder 4), 1978 (Folder 49: 9-10)
  - Letters about Austin Inaugural Committee, Bohemian Club, and oil industry, clippings on Jimmy Carter, economics, and politics (Binder 4) (contd.), 1978 (Folder 50: 1-2)
  - Letter from George Bush, inauguration of William Clements, Marine Military Academy, clippings on various countries and politics (Binder 1), 1979 (Folder 50: 3-6)
  - Letters from William Clements, memorial of Elliott, clippings on Africa, George Bush, and oil industry (Binder 2), 1979-1980 (Folder 50: 7-10)
- Correspondence, subject file, and printed matter, 1915-1979
  Contains material not included in Elliott's scrapbooks, such as correspondence from Welton J. Crook and printed matter on Stanford and the oil industry. Arranged alphabetically by format.
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1952 (Folder 51: 1)
    - Barnes, 1975 (Folder 51: 2)
      Letter to Ruth Elliott
    - Crook, Welton J., 1969-1974 (Folder 51: 3)
    - Ruetz, Joseph H., 1970 (Folder 51: 4)
      Includes report of the Stanford President's Advisory Committee on ROTC Affairs
    - Symonds, Gardiner, 1968 (Folder 51: 5)
  - Miscellany, 1957, undated (Folder 51: 6)
  - Printed matter
    - General, 1952-1979, undated (Folder 51: 7-10)
    - Oil industry
      - "The Oil Region of Northeastern Mexico,", 1915 (Folder 51: 11)
      - The Geological and Mining Society of American Universities, Stanford University, Yearbook and Directory, 1915, 1921 (Folder 51: 12)
      - Directory of American Institute of Mining and Metallurgical Engineers, Inc., 1952 (Folder 52: 1)
      - Directory of Stanford Mineral Scientists, 1952 (Folder 52: 2)
      - "County Correlation for Texas Oil,", 1954 (Folder 52: 3)
      - "Pleistocene Age of the 'Eocene' Ridgway Till, Colorado," by Kirtley Mather and Sherman Wengerd, 1965 (Folder 52: 4)
      - West Texas Geological Society, Permian Basin Section Society of Economic Paleontologists and Mineralogists, Permian Basin Geophysical Society, and Permian Basin Well Logging Society Membership Directory, 1966-1967 (Folder 52: 5)
      - "Crusta Movements in the Arabia Region," by L. F. Ivanhoe, 1967 (Folder 52: 6)